<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ad-absurdum.me</title>
    <link>https://ad-absurdum.me</link>
    <description>So many ideas so little time</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 12:59:56 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <ttl>1440</ttl>
    <atom:link href="https://ad-absurdum.me/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spring-Loaded Dinosaurs: What Penguins, Kiwis, and Armored Core Get Right (and Wrong) About Legs</title>
      <link>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/spring-loaded-dinosaurs</link>
      <guid>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/spring-loaded-dinosaurs</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <description>Look at a penguin skeleton side-on and you&apos;d be forgiven for thinking you&apos;re looking at a small theropod dinosaur. Upright posture, forward-leaning stance, stubby vestigial forelimbs, powerful hind legs. The kiwi is arguably even more convincing — its wings are so reduced they&apos;re invisible, leavi...</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Passive Velocity Sorting: A Geometric Maxwell&apos;s Demon?</title>
      <link>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/maxwells-demon-sorting</link>
      <guid>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/maxwells-demon-sorting</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <description>If sorting had deep thermodynamic costs, these industrial processes shouldn&apos;t work so cheaply. But they do.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AC Gravity and Gravitational Opacity</title>
      <link>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/alternating-gravity</link>
      <guid>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/alternating-gravity</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <description>Imagine a planetoid with a dense ball floating above it, oscillating up and down sinusoidally. This creates an &quot;AC gravity&quot; field - a time-varying gravitational influence on objects below.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theorem: Equivalence of -arccoth and tan Functions</title>
      <link>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/infinitely-fat-tan-conjecture</link>
      <guid>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/infinitely-fat-tan-conjecture</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <description>Imagine you could take the most repetitive, oscillating function in mathematics—the tangent function—and transform it into something that never repeats. It sounds impossible, but that&apos;s exactly what we&apos;ve discovered. By stretching tan&apos;s period to 2-infinity and shifting it by 1-infinity, we can m...</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Photonic Transformer Hypothesis: Rethinking Photosynthesis and Methane Consumption in Plants</title>
      <link>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/photonic-transformer-hypothesis</link>
      <guid>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/photonic-transformer-hypothesis</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <description>This document proposes a radical reinterpretation of photosynthesis mechanisms, suggesting that plants may function as biological infrared (IR) lasers, using frequency downconversion to create transparent energy channels. This hypothesis could explain the presence of red-pigmented plants in metha...</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Scalable Quasi-Perpetual Photonic Machine</title>
      <link>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/sort-of-perpetual-motion-machine</link>
      <guid>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/sort-of-perpetual-motion-machine</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <description>We present a theoretically sound, thermodynamically compliant system that achieves effectively perpetual motion through geometric scaling. By circulating photons between rail-constrained atoms in a hexagonal configuration, we demonstrate that operational lifetime scales quadratically with system ...</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Make a Ball Orbit Itself</title>
      <link>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/how-to-make-a-ball-orbit-itself</link>
      <guid>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/how-to-make-a-ball-orbit-itself</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <description>src=&quot;/blog/how-to-make-a-ball-orbit-itself/ball_orbit_animation.html&quot;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Boron-Nitrogen Catastrophe: A Critical Gap in Beta Decay Verification</title>
      <link>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/boron-nitrogen-catastrophe</link>
      <guid>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/boron-nitrogen-catastrophe</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <description>Standard nuclear physics claims that Carbon-14 undergoes beta decay to produce Nitrogen-14:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>X-Ray Data Pipeline: Ultra-High-Speed Communication Through Limestone Tubes</title>
      <link>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/x-ray-data-pipelines</link>
      <guid>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/x-ray-data-pipelines</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <description>A revolutionary approach to data transmission using X-ray beams through limestone/concrete tubes, potentially achieving **10-100 Tbps** per channel at a fraction of current infrastructure costs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Universal Approximation Theorem Is Right. You&apos;re Using It Wrong.</title>
      <link>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/universal-approximation-theorem-is-right</link>
      <guid>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/universal-approximation-theorem-is-right</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <description>Ask any ML student about the XOR problem and you&apos;ll hear: &quot;XOR is impossible for a single-layer perceptron. You need a hidden layer to solve it.&quot;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power Law Illusion: A Measurement Artifact Hypothesis</title>
      <link>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/the-power-law-illusion</link>
      <guid>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/the-power-law-illusion</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <description>Many phenomena we interpret as following power law distributions may actually be one tail of underlying bell-shaped (Gaussian, Poisson, or other unimodal) distributions. We observe apparent power laws because we systematically measure only one side of these distributions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fractional Gamma Function via Fractional Derivatives</title>
      <link>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/fractional-gamma-function</link>
      <guid>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/fractional-gamma-function</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <description>The classical gamma function  is one of the most important special functions in mathematics, serving as a continuous extension of the factorial function. It satisfies the fundamental recurrence relation , which represents a &quot;unit step&quot; in the argument.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the cruel irony of the P-NP problem</title>
      <link>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/cruel-irony-of-p-np-problem</link>
      <guid>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/cruel-irony-of-p-np-problem</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <description>If you&apos;re not familiar with the P-NP problem, it&apos;s one of the major unsolved conundrums in computer science, challenging experts for over fifty years. It delves into the realms of time complexity and the intrinsic difficulty of computational problems. Often, media outlets simplify this by referri...</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Journey from India to Germany: A Guide for IT Professionals</title>
      <link>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/immigrating-to-germany</link>
      <guid>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/immigrating-to-germany</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <description>Embarking on an international move can be a daunting task, particularly when it involves navigating through the intricate immigration process. Here, I&apos;ve compiled a step-by-step guide for my fellow IT professionals considering a move from India to Germany.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How does AutoGPT work under the hood?</title>
      <link>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/how-autogpt-works-under-the-hood</link>
      <guid>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/how-autogpt-works-under-the-hood</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <description>There are many youtube videos and blog posts about AutoGPT, but none of them peek under the hood and examine the code itself. So, I have gone through the code and I will provide a quick overview of how it works and some interesting parts of the code which I found to be unexpected. This is not mea...</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unit Test Recorder - Automatically generate unit tests as you use your application</title>
      <link>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/unit-test-recorder</link>
      <guid>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/unit-test-recorder</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <description>This is a write up for the npm package unit-test-recorder or UTR for short.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to migrate from vanilla Kubernetes to Istio service mesh?</title>
      <link>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/migrate-to-istio</link>
      <guid>https://ad-absurdum.me/blog/migrate-to-istio</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <description>The goal of this guide is to give the reader the most concise and non-intimidating introduction to istio while simultaneously providing further reading material if it piques his interest.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>